PLAMEN PASLIEV

Luderitzstrasse 9, 13351, Berlin (+49) 1783 340 497, plamen_pasliev@abv.bg Portfolio website: https://plamenpasliev.github.io/

SUMMARY

Data Science MSc graduate with 2+ years of experience in project work. Team player with the desire to solve business problems using machine learning and data analytics tools. Worked on all development levels from problem formulation to pushing models to production.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wayfair GmbH Data Scientist Jun 2019 - Present Berlin, Germany

• Fraud Detection

- Performed extensive exploratory data analysis (EDA) to identify important features which correlate to fraudulent orders.
- Developed an MVP fraud detection model (CatBoost) with over 86% F1 score.
- Predicting Customer Problems
 - Personalized the Help and Contact page of Wayfair.
 - Developed different machine learning solutions such as GBDT (XGBoost and CatBoost) and a neural network (Keras with TensorFlow) with top-3 accuracy of 90%.
 - Updated and maintained models deployed in production (Airflow).
 - Worked on collecting and processing data, data exploration, modelling, testing and pushing to production.
- Resolution Optimization for Damaged/Defective Products
 - Used Python libraries such as matplotlib and seaborn to visualize the relationship between resolutions and customer engagement.

Technology stack: Python, MSSQL, Vertica, Hive, Git, Airflow, Docker

Neurocat GmbH

Apr 2019 - Jun 2019

Berlin, Germany

Artificial Intelligence Intern

- Integrated and tested popular explanation methods using Python and TensorFlow.
- Researched explanation methods and proposed a systematic approach to categorize them.

Technology stack: Python (Numpy, Pandas, TensorFlow, PyTest)

$\begin{array}{c} \textbf{Technical University of Eindhoven} \\ \textit{Student mentor} \end{array}$

Aug 2016 - Feb 2017 Eindhoven, Netherlands

• Organized individual and group weekly meetings with twenty-four first-year students.

• Taught effective study skills and helped in practical matters.

EDUCATION

EIT Digital Master School

Sep 2017 - Feb 2020

MSc in Data Science

Berlin, Germany / Milan, Italy

- \cdot Double-degree master program combining technical education with innovation and entrepreneurship.
- · Obtained two MSc degrees, awarded from Technische Universitat Berlin and Politecnico di Milano, as well as the EIT certificate.
- · Awarded a two-year, merit-based, scholarship including a tuition fee weaver and monthly allowances.

Technical University of Eindhoven

BSc in Computer Science and Software Engineering

September 2014 - July 2017 Eindhoven, Netherlands

- Acquired knowledge about theory, algorithms, software development, system architecture, data structures and information systems.
- Took part in many software engineering group projects. From app development in Java to web development with HTML, JavaScript, Angular, NodeJS, Firebase NoSQL. Practiced agile development and Scrum.

PROJECTS

Training Neural Networks with Manipulated Explanations Technische Universität Berlin Master's thesis Apr 2019 - Feb 2020

- Used PvTorch to train image recognition models with over 92% accuracy.
- Extended current research and showed how popular explanation methods can be manipulated critically.

Visualizing Immobilienscout listings

Jan 2020

- Scraped over 3000 active listings from immobilienscout24 to improve visualization.
- Created an interactive web page: https://plamenpasliev.github.io/pages/housing.html

Neural Style Transfer for Furniture (Wayfair hackathon)

Dec 2019

- Used Keras and TensorFlow to generate artificial pieces of furniture fitting a desired home style.
- Beat hundreds of engineers and reached the final eight.

Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp

Mar 2019

• Certificate of completion: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-5OH1TL0O/

Machine Learning for Financial Data

Summer School

Budapest, Hungary Jul 2018-Aug 2018

- Business idea for predicting the influx of customers of SMEs via machine learning.
- Awarded second place out of eight groups.

Recommender System 2017 Challenge

Recommender Systems course

Politecnico di Milano Sep 2017 - Feb 2018

- Used data from over 1M interactions (100K tracks belonging to 57K playlists) to recommend songs to users.
- Created an ensemble of machine learning solutions such as Collaborative filtering, Content-based filtering and Sparse Linear Method (SLIM) which outperformed individual methods.

SKILLS

Python stack

Programming languages

Databases

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Data Analysis and Data Visualization

Data Cleaning and Data Manipulation

Version Control

Workflow management Interpersonal Skills

Agile methodologies

Mathematics

Languages

NumPy, Pandas, SciPy, Jupyter Notebooks

Python, Java, Javascript

MSSQL, Vertica, Hive, PostgreSQL, Firebase NoSQL

Scikit-learn

PyTorch, Keras, TensorFlow

Matplotlib, Seaborn

NumPy, Pandas, SciPy, sklearn

Apache Airflow

Presentation, Teamwork, Communication, Organization

Scrum

Probability, Statistics, Linear Algebra

English (full professional proficiency), Bulgarian (native)

HOBBIES

Reading, sports, meditation, mindfulness, self-help, travelling, video games. Active gym member for the past decade. Interested in the science behind nutrition and different training patterns.